Finding Aid for Assistant to the President (University of Michigan) Records, 1913-1986
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Reports, background materials, etc.
  - Student Participation in University Affairs: Introduction and Summary, 1965 (Box 48)
  - The Higher, The Fewer--Report and Recommendations of the Committee to Study the Status of Women in Graduate Education and Later Careers, 1974 (Box 48)
  - University of Michigan's Equal Employment Opportunity Affirmative Action Program Projection of Goals and Target Dates, 1969 (Box 49)
  - University Hospital Study and Advisory Committee Report to the President, 1968 (Box 49)
  - State Plan for Higher Education in Michigan (plus background materials), 1969 (Box 49)
- Outstanding Achievement Award
  - 1964-1973, 10 folders (Box 52)
- Topical Files
  - Chinese University Presidents Delegation, 1986 (Box 53)
  - Fleming Building Dedication April, 1981 (Box 53)
  - Fleming Presidential Dinner January, 1979 (Box 53)
  - Ford Library Dedication April, 1981 (Box 53)
  - Men's Glee Club Tours (UM)
    - 1963 (Box 53)
    - 1971 (Box 53)
    - 1978 (Box 53)
    - 1984-1986 (Box 53)
  - Mott Children's Hospital Dedication, 1969 (Box 53)
  - Operation Michigan January-June, 1964 (Box 53)
  - Peace Corps, 20th anniversary, 1980 (Box 53)
  - Power Center Groundbreaking April, 1969 (Box 53)
  - President's Conference on the University March, 1964 (Box 53)
  - Queen Beatrix of the Netherlands' Visit June, 1982 (Box 53)
  - Stolper (Professor Emeritus Wolfgang F.) Reception December, 1981 (Box 53)
  - Symphony Band (UM), Eastern European Tour, 1961 (Box 53)
  - UM 164 January, 1964 (Box 53)
  - University Calendar Study Committee, 1957-1959; 4 folders (Box 53)
  - Visiting Committee Program April, 1962 (Box 53)
- Henry Russel Lecturer
  - 1978/79-1985/86, 8 folders (Box 55)
- Outstanding Achievement Award
  - 1974-1979, 6 folders (Box 55)
- Photographs
  - Topical
    - Campus Buildings
      - Central Campus, undated (Box 56)
      - Medical Center, undated (Box 56)
      - North Campus, undated (Box 56)
    - Choral Union (includes Dr. Albert Stanley and Frieze Memorial Organ) (Box 56)
    - Miscellaneous People, including university officials, award recipients, and visiting dignitaries, 3 envelopes (Box 56)
  - Commencement
    - Winter-1985 Winter, 1975; 27 envelopes (Box 56)
  - Henry Russel Lecturer
    - 1978/79-1980/81, 3 envelopes (Box 56)
  - Honors Convocation
    - 1981-1985, 5 envelopes (Box 56)
  - Outstanding Achievement Award
    - 1975-1979, 5 folders (Box 56)
  - State of the University Addresses
    - 1980-1984, 5 folders (Box 56)
- Erich Walter files
  (assistant to the president and secretary of the University)
  - Correspondence, 1945-1966 (Box 57)
    (arranged alphabetically; also one folder of letters of Don Curto, 1945-1946 reporting in part on his wartime service and on his observation of the Communist Revolution in China)
  - Topical files, 1958-1970
    (also includes files of successor Herbert W. Hildebrandt)
    - A (Box 58)
    - Athletic Plant, 1963 (Box 58)
    - B (Box 58)
    - Bentley, Alvin, 1966-1968 (Box 58)
    - Brablec, Carl, 1959-1968 (Box 58)
    - Bridges, Harriet, 1961 (Box 58)
      (regarding sharing dorm room with African American)
    - C (Box 58)
    - Campbell (Chesser M. Campbell Fund), 1960-1968 (Box 58)
    - Carpenter, Arthur E., 1958 (Box 58)
    - Conference on the University, 1961-1962 (Box 58)
    - Connable, Alfred B., 1960-1964 (Box 58)
    - Cudlip, William B., 1963-1973 (Box 58)
    - D (Box 58)
    - DeFoe, Frederuck W. Memorial Scholarship, 1959 (Box 58)
    - Delata College, 1962-1963 (Box 58)
    - E (Box 58)
    - F (Box 58)
    - G (Box 58)
    - H (Box 58)
    - I (Box 58)
    - J (Box 58)
    - K (Box 58)
    - Kennedy, Charles S., 1959-1965 (Box 58)
    - L (Box 58)
    - Mc (Box 58)
    - McInally, W.K., 1959-1964 (Box 58)
    - M (Box 58)
    - Marsh, Mrs. Phil A., 1961-1968 (Box 58)
    - Matthaei, Frederick, 1960-1967 (Box 58)
    - Murphy, Irene, 1958-1967 (Box 58)
    - N (Box 58)
    - O (Box 58)
    - Osborn, Mrs. Chase S., 1959-1962 (Box 58)
    - Oxford Housing Project, 1962 (Box 58)
    - P (Box 58)
    - R (Box 58)
    - Reese, Donald J., 1961-1964 (Box 58)
    - Regents, 1959-1963 (Box 58)
    - Regents meetings, 1970; 2 folders (Box 58)
    - S (Box 58)
    - Sorenson, Allan, 1961-1968 (Box 58)
    - T (Box 58)
    - Thurber, Donald, 1959-1961 (Box 58)
    - Union-League merger (proposed), 1963 (Box 58)
    - V (Box 58)
    - W (Box 58)
    - Watkins, Herbert, 1962-1968 (Box 58)
    - X-Z (Box 58)